## **VLADISLAV S. STEERE**

Dallas, TX 75089

**Phone:** (803) 606-8902 | **Email:** vssteere@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/vladislavsteere/ | GitHub: https://github.com/vsteere |

Portfolio: https://vsteere.github.io/Responsive Portfolio/

#### SUMMARY

Back-end web developer with six years of public finance and budgeting experience. A professional with a proven track record of on-time project deliveries, process improvement, and a passion for problem solving and developing intuitive web-based tools.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: HTML5/CSS3, Javascript (ES5 and ES6), VBA, MySQL

Technologies: Bootstrap, Node.js, REST APIs, Express.js, React.js, Git, AJAX, JSON, jQuery,

Handlebars, MongoDB.

#### **PROJECTS**

## Meally Food Delivery Manager | https://tinyurl.com/Meally-Delivery-Manager | https://meally-food-delivery-tracker.herokuapp.com/

- Description: Full-stack MCV application for drivers or businesses to track food deliveries from order creation to delivery.
- Responsibilities: back-end logic development including Node.js server, MySQL database, and REST APIs.
- Technologies used: Node.js, Sequelize ORM, REST APIs, and Handlebars templating engine.

## Team Profile Generator | https://github.com/vsteere/Team\_Profile\_Generator | https://tinyurl.com/Team-Profile-Generator

- Description: CLI application to dynamically develop an organizational structure through interactive data inputs. Once complete, an HTML page is generated with the user's data.
- Responsibilities: Back-end logic development including data input interface.
- Technologies used: Javascript, Node.js, Inquirer package, and jQuery.

## North Texas Brews and Chews | https://github.com/vsteere/Project\_1-Brews\_and\_Chews | https://vsteere.github.io/Project\_1-Brews\_and\_Chews/

- Description: Application that allows users to find restaurants and breweries in North Texas through keyword, cuisine choice, and city selection.
- Responsibilities: Project Manager and back-end logic development including AJAX queries.
- Technologies used: Javascript, jQuery, Bootstrap, AJAX, Bootstrap, and W3Schools CSS framework.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Senior Financial Analyst City of Grand Prairie, TX

2019 - Present

Develop and manage multiple city agencies' operating budgets in excess of \$5 million. Liaise with the Finance Department to develop the city's tax and fee rates including property taxes and utility rates.

### Key Accomplishments:

- Administer and maintain Budget Development Microsoft Access database, including updating tables and user forms.
- Developed and deployed multiple VBA subroutines to automate and significantly simplify enduser report generation processes. The deployment of the subroutines saved the user on average 10 minutes per report.

### Budget Officer 2018 - 2019 City of Rowlett, TX

Responsible for the development and management of the city's operating and capital budgets. Coordinated with departments to develop revenue and expenditure forecasts using multiple data analysis methodologies. Briefed City Council on budget related topics during public meetings and workshops.

### Key Accomplishments:

- Served as the project manager and functional lead for Priority Based Budgeting cloud software solution implementation. Advised City Manager on project milestones to ensure software was ready for Fiscal Year 2021 budget development.
- Served as the City's Investment Officer, managing a \$45 million portfolio. Liaised with a financial advisor firm to ensure cash was invested within policy guidelines. Developed a strategy to invest capital bond funds based on project timelines, generating thousands of interest earnings.

## Senior Budget and Management Analyst Broward County, FL

2014 - 2018

Managed and developed county agency operating and capital budget. Liaised with Broward Sheriff's Office to manage their \$1 billion annual public safety operating budget. Consulted with agencies to streamline their internal processes and performance metrics.

#### Key Accomplishments:

- Designed user forms and workflows and led User Acceptance Testing sessions during implementation of Oracle Planning and Budgeting Cloud Services (PBCS) and Enterprise Performance Reporting Cloud (EPRCS) solutions.
- Trained department staff, post-implementation, on Oracle PeopleSoft Financials modules.
- Collaborated with County stakeholders and Microsoft consultants to develop and implement an on-premise dashboard application to better track the County's detention data and trends.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Web Development Bootcamp Certificate:** Southern Methodist University, Dallas, TX A six-month program focused on full-stack agile web development. Covered technologies included jQuery, JSON, APIs, Express, Node.js, and React.js.

Master of Public Administration: Texas A&M University, College Station, TX

Bachelor of Arts in International Studies: University of South Carolina, Columbia, SC